

# MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

# **SUMMARY**

Motivated applied Al leader with more than 10 years of experience in Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning. Team player dedicated to promoting a culture of trust and personal growth. Proven track record of bringing evidence-based innovation into products.

# LEADERSHIP HIGHLIGHTS

- A proven record of enabling innovation through aligning product goals with science capabilities.
- Years of experience in communicating complex scientific concepts to senior leaders and a wide range of stakeholders.
- Built a science team of 6 from the ground up, establishing a culture of trust, innovation, and professional growth.
- Established academic publishing as part of product decision-making based on empirical evidence.

# **MAJOR PROJECTS**

### **Note Assistant**

2019-2022

My team was part of a wider cross-functional product team that designed and delivered a live consultation summarisation system for Babylon's Clinical Portal, which decreased the documentation time during consultations with nurses by 17%.

- We followed a double-diamond product design strategy, to deliver a product feature improving the clinician's efficiency and experience.
- Our data preparation, model architecture, and release strategy had to balance our delivery goals against Data Privacy and Clinical Safety regulations.
- I designed a protocol that made human evaluation more reliable and up to 50% more efficient.
- Consistently published all notable experiments within the bounds of the commercially prudent.
- Co-supervised a Babylon-funded industrial PhD for one of my reports (submission expected in H1 2023).

## **Clinical Information Extraction Stack**

2018-2022

My team and I designed, delivered, and maintained the clinical information extraction system that underpins multiple Babylon technologies and products (e.g. intent recognition, health graph, consultation summarisation), including an <u>open-source</u> rule engine Hammurabi.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Sussex PhD in Clinical NLP, 2012-2015

University of Tübingen

BA & MA in Computational Linguistics, 2003-2009

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

ML • Huggingface • PyTorch • deepspeed • Keras

Python • spaCy • NLTK • FastAPI • Flask • Cython

CI • Docker • Kubernetes • CircleCI • GitHub Actions

Data • MySQL • PostgreSQL • Redis • Kafka • MongoDB

Cloud • AWS • GCP

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Head of Al

JABS MedTech, May 2023 to present

As head of AI, I led the company's AI strategy through the initial product discovery, two grant applications and an RFP. As an engineer, I focused on building a flexible, distributed AI system to support safe and explainable clinical AI capabilities at a massive scale.

## Al Consultant (contracts)

Cool Den AI, Feb 2023 to May 2023

I help startups improve their use of AI, from the deployment of machine learning models to their AI product strategy.

### Applied Al Research Manager

Babylon Health, Jun 2019 to Dec 2022

As a leader, I aligned our research work closer to the product needs, promoted an end-to-end ownership model for AI services, and introduced product design best practices to our development process.

## **Senior NLP Scientist**

Babylon Health, Dec 2018 to May 2019

As the tech lead of the NLP squad, I was focused on supporting the Chatbot product through Information Extraction and Intent Recognition technologies. In addition was part of setting up Babylon's Speech Processing.

## **NLP Scientist**

Babylon Health, Feb 2017 to Nov 2018

I led the modernisation of the Information Extraction stack, moving it to Python and allowing it to interface with bleeding-edge technologies. Additionally, I designed the hiring process for the NLP team.

## **Data Scientist**

Datamaran, Sep 2015 to Jan 2017

I designed and delivered a news analytics module for the Datamaran platform, based on a streaming data ingestion system.

# **Research Assisstant**

Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, Apr 2010 to Dec 2011

I worked on a Bulgarian-English machine translation system.

## SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Google Scholar: http://scholar.sasho.io

- Consultation Checklists: Standardising the Human Evaluation of Medical Note Generation, Savkov et al. 2022, EMNLP.
- User-Driven Research of Medical Note Generation Software,

Knoll et al. 2022, NAACL. (Best Paper Award)

 $\hbox{-} \textit{Primock 57: A dataset of primary care mock consultations,} \\$ 

Korfiatis et al. 2022, ACL

- Don't Settle for Average, Go for the Max: Fuzzy Sets and Max-Pooled Word Vectors, **Zhelezniak et al. 2019, ICLR**